Deepsea Challenge 3D is a documentary film directed by Andrew Wight.
Described as being a film about determination, danger and the ocean’s greatest depths, James Cameron's "Deepsea
Challenge 3D" tells the story of Cameron’s journey to fulfill his boyhood dream of becoming an explorer.
The movie offers a unique insight into Cameron's world as he makes that dream reality – and makes
history – by becoming the first person to travel solo to the deepest point on the planet.
Self, played by James Cameron.
Self, played by Suzy Amis.
Giuseppe Buono, played by Frank Lotito.
Jacques Piccard, played by Lachlan Woods.
Don Walsh, played by Paul Henri.
Deepsea Challenger (DCV 1) is a 7.3-metre (24 ft) deep-diving submersible designed to
reach the bottom of the Challenger Deep, the deepest-known point on Earth.
On 26 March 2012, Canadian film director James Cameron piloted the craft to
accomplish this goal in the second crewed dive reaching the Challenger Deep.
Built in Sydney, Australia, by the research and design company Acheron Project Pty Ltd, Deepsea Challenger includes scientific sampling equipment
and high-definition 3-D cameras; it reached the ocean's deepest point after two hours and 36 minutes of descent from the surface.
The film explores themes of diving, deep sea,
underwater, nature, nature documentary.
The tone is thought_provoking.